<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Partitions on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/partitions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Partitions on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 16:05:02 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/partitions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing Storage: Creating Partitions</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/managing-storage-creating-partitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 16:05:02 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/managing-storage-creating-partitions/</guid>
      <description>To match the different partition types we use different partitioning utilities. The fdisk utlity is used to create MBR partitions while the gdisk utility is used to create GPT paritions.
Apart from fdisk and gdisk, there is the parted command which can create both MBR and GPT partitions but has less advanced features.
Each command takes a disk device name as an argument. The device names are usually /dev/sda, /dev/sdb, &amp;hellip; in the order the device is recognized by the kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Storage: Understanding MBR and GPT Partitions</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/managing-storage-understanding-mbr-and-gpt-partitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 17:45:50 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/managing-storage-understanding-mbr-and-gpt-partitions/</guid>
      <description>If a mass storage device is connected to a Linux computer, the Linux kernel tries to locate any partitions. So to use a hard drive we need to partition it. On RHEL 8 two different partitioning schemes are available: the Master Boot Record and GUID Partition Table. Linux typically has multiple partitions on one hard disk, this makes sense for different reasons:
 Distinguish different types of data. Mount options to enhance security or performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
