<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CentOS on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/centos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CentOS on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/centos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Let’s Encrypt SSL with Certbot on Centos 8</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/automate-lets-encrypt-ssl-with-certbot-on-centos-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/automate-lets-encrypt-ssl-with-certbot-on-centos-8/</guid>
      <description>An SSL Certificate is a text file with encrypted data that you install on your server so that you can secure/encrypt sensitive communications between your site and your visitors. They are also used to verify that you are connected with the service you wish to be connecting with, and, as a website owner it validates your trustworthiness.
SSL certificates can be expensive, so here&amp;rsquo;s where Let’s Encrypt comes into play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Nginx and Setting up Server Blocks on CentOS 8</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/installing-nginx-and-setting-up-server-blocks-on-centos-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/installing-nginx-and-setting-up-server-blocks-on-centos-8/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to install Nginx and set up Nginx server blocks on CentOS 8, and, how to serve different content to different visitors depending on which domains they are requesting.
After initially installing CentOS, check if updates are available and apply them:
$ sudo dnf update -y firewalld Next, let&amp;rsquo;s install the firewalld daemon to secure the server, start the daemon and enable it at boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8 and Nvidia Optimus</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/red-hat-enterprise-linux-8-and-nvidia-optimus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 06:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/red-hat-enterprise-linux-8-and-nvidia-optimus/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I decided to go ahead and install RHEL8 on my laptop and use it as my everyday workstation as well as a learning platform to move forward on my Red Hat certification path.
In case you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can actually use RHEL for free with a No-Cost RHEL Developer Subscription as long as you don&amp;rsquo;t use the machine &amp;ldquo;in production&amp;rdquo;.
After a pretty straightforward installation of RHEL 8 I was immediately confronted with a first issue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
