<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advanced Storage on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/advanced-storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advanced Storage on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/advanced-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Storage: Virtual Data Optimizer</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-virtual-data-optimizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-virtual-data-optimizer/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Data Optimizer is a storage solution developed to reduce disk space usage on block devices by applying deduplication features. VDO creates volumes on top of any existing block device from where you either create an XFS file system, or use the volume as a Physical Volume in an LVM setup.
VDO uses three common technologies:
 Zero-block elimination to filter out data blocks that contain only zeros. Deduplication of redundant data blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Storage: Configuring Stratis</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-configuring-stratis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-configuring-stratis/</guid>
      <description>Stratis, created as an answer to Btrfs and ZFS by Red Hat, is a volume-managing file system that introduces advanced storage features like:
 Thin-provisioning: The file system presents itself to users as much bigger than it really is. Useful in virtualized environments. Snapshots: Allows users to backup the current state of the file system and makes it easy to revert to a previous state. Cache tier: A Ceph storage feature that ensures data is stored physically closer to the Ceph client, making data access faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Storage: Logical Volume Manager</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-logical-volume-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/advanced-storage-logical-volume-manager/</guid>
      <description>Understanding LVM The Logical Volume Manager was introduced to workaround some restrictions that come with standard partitions. The most important restriction would be inflexibility, with LVM you can dynamically grow a partition even if the disk itself is running out of space.
In the LVM architecture we can distinguish several layers. The lowest layer contains the storage devices, these can be anything from regular disks to partions and logical units (LUNs) on a storage-area network (SAN).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
