<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSL on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/categories/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSL on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/categories/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CloudFlare Authenticated Origin Pulls</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/cloudflare-authenticated-origin-pulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/cloudflare-authenticated-origin-pulls/</guid>
      <description>In addition to my previous post on blocking requests that are hitting my websites directly without going through the CloudFlare network, we can enable the Authenticated Origin Pulls feature.
Authenticated Origin Pulls uses TLS Authentication to verify that the server hosting my website is communicating with CloudFlare and not some other server or client.
Nginx will be configured to only accept requests which use a valid client certificate from Cloudflare and requests which have not passed through CloudFlare will be dropped: The server will respond with a 400 Bad Request status code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Let’s Encrypt SSL with Certbot on Centos 8</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/automate-lets-encrypt-ssl-with-certbot-on-centos-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 08:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/automate-lets-encrypt-ssl-with-certbot-on-centos-8/</guid>
      <description>An SSL Certificate is a text file with encrypted data that you install on your server so that you can secure/encrypt sensitive communications between your site and your visitors. They are also used to verify that you are connected with the service you wish to be connecting with, and, as a website owner it validates your trustworthiness.
SSL certificates can be expensive, so here&amp;rsquo;s where Let’s Encrypt comes into play.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
