<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>centos8 on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/centos8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in centos8 on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:03:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/tags/centos8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Network on RHEL 8 with nmcli and nmtui</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/configuring-the-network-on-rhel-8-with-nmcli-and-nmtui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 08:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/configuring-the-network-on-rhel-8-with-nmcli-and-nmtui/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post we learned how the check the runtime configuration of the network using the ip command. To make persistent changes to the network configuration that will survive a reboot, we need to use either nmcli or nmtui.
Networking is managed by the NetworkManager service. When the NetworkManager service comes up, it reads the network card configuration scripts that are located in /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts and that have a name which starts with ifcgf followed by the name of the network card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating Network Configuration on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/validating-network-configuration-on-red-hat-enterprise-linux-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 17:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/validating-network-configuration-on-red-hat-enterprise-linux-8/</guid>
      <description>Networking is one of the essential items on a server. On Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8, networking is managed by the NetworkManager service. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover new tools that were introduced to help manage networks during runtime and how to make make the configuration persistent.
Validating Network Addresses and Interfaces In RHEL 8, the default names for network cards are based on firmware, device topology, and device firmware. Network card names will always consist of the following parts:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
