<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nginx on Joeri JM Smissaert</title>
    <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/categories/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nginx on Joeri JM Smissaert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joerismissaert.dev/terms-of-service&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joerismissaert.dev/categories/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CloudFlare Authenticated Origin Pulls</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/cloudflare-authenticated-origin-pulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/cloudflare-authenticated-origin-pulls/</guid>
      <description>In addition to my previous post on blocking requests that are hitting my websites directly without going through the CloudFlare network, we can enable the Authenticated Origin Pulls feature.
Authenticated Origin Pulls uses TLS Authentication to verify that the server hosting my website is communicating with CloudFlare and not some other server or client.
Nginx will be configured to only accept requests which use a valid client certificate from Cloudflare and requests which have not passed through CloudFlare will be dropped: The server will respond with a 400 Bad Request status code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking requests not originating from CloudFlare on Nginx</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/blocking-requests-not-originating-from-cloudflare-on-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 07:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/blocking-requests-not-originating-from-cloudflare-on-nginx/</guid>
      <description>My websites are behind CloudFlare , which acts as a reverse proxy and which can help in mitigating attacks, malicious traffic and requests.
CloudFlare is masking the real IP address of this site. If you look up the DNS A record for this domain, you&amp;rsquo;ll see one of CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s IP addresses. Essentially, CloudFlare is forwarding traffic from their servers to the server where my sites are hosted.
The inconvenience of this is that I can&amp;rsquo;t see the real IP address of the visitor, instead, I&amp;rsquo;m seeing CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s IP addresses in the Nginx log.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Nginx and Setting up Server Blocks on CentOS 8</title>
      <link>https://joerismissaert.dev/installing-nginx-and-setting-up-server-blocks-on-centos-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joerismissaert.dev/installing-nginx-and-setting-up-server-blocks-on-centos-8/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to install Nginx and set up Nginx server blocks on CentOS 8, and, how to serve different content to different visitors depending on which domains they are requesting.
After initially installing CentOS, check if updates are available and apply them:
$ sudo dnf update -y firewalld Next, let&amp;rsquo;s install the firewalld daemon to secure the server, start the daemon and enable it at boot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
